selfhacked.com 2019-10-11

# Selfhacked Privacy Policy - SelfHacked

#### SelfHacked Privacy Policy

 **Last Updated July 25, 2018**

SelfHacked® and SelfHacked.com (“SelfHacked”) recognize the importance of protecting the privacy of your personal information, and we have prepared this Privacy Policy to provide you with important information about our privacy practices. This Privacy Policy applies when you use a website, or other online service (collectively, the “Services”) that links or refers to it. It does not govern or apply to information collected or used by SelfHacked® and SelfHacked.com through other means. 

If you are a user in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or Switzerland, please see the  **Users in the EEA and Switzerland** section of this Privacy Policy for additional provisions that are applicable to your use of the Services. 

This Privacy Policy covers the following:

We may collect personal information about our users in various ways. For example, we may collect information that you provide to us, information that we collect through your use of the Services, and information that we collect from publicly available sources or third parties. 

**Information You Provide to Us.  **When you register or otherwise interact with the Services, you may be invited to provide personal information to enhance your experience on the Services. For example, during account registration, we may ask for information such as your name, e-mail address, year of birth, gender, street address, job title and industry and related information. We may collect payment information, such as your credit card number and expiration date, where appropriate to process a financial transaction you have requested. 

We also collect information that you provide us when you comment on articles, participate in message boards, and submit images, photos, videos, or other content to the Services. We may ask you for additional information at other times, such as when you enter a contest or participate in a promotion, when you post an online ad, or when you order products from us or otherwise engage with the Services. 

**Information About Your Use of the Services.  **In addition to the information you provide to us directly, we may collect information about your use of the Services. For example, we may collect: 

  * _Device information_ — such as your hardware model, IP address, other unique device identifiers, operating system version, browser type and settings, such as language and available font settings, and settings of the device you use to access the Services.
  *  _Usage information_ — such as information about the Services you use, the time and duration of your use of the Services and other information about your interaction with content offered through a Service, and any information stored using cookies, mobile ad identifiers, and similar technologies that we have set on your device. For detailed information about our use of cookies, web beacons, and other technologies, see the  **Online Tracking and Advertising** section below.
  *  _Location information_ — such as your computer’s IP address, your mobile device’s GPS signal or information about nearby WiFi access points and cell towers that may be transmitted to us when you use certain Services.

**Information From Third-Party Sources.  **We may receive information about you from publicly and commercially available sources, as permitted by law, which we may combine with other information we receive from or about you. For example, we may receive information about you from a social media site if you connect to the Services through that site. 

**Other Information We Collect.  **We also may collect other information about you, your device, or your use of the services in ways that we describe to you at the point of collection or otherwise with your consent. You may choose not to provide us with certain types of information, but doing so may affect your ability to use some of the Services.

 **To Provide and Manage the Services You Request.  **This includes, for example, processing your subscription, sending you electronic newsletters, or enabling you to participate in the features provided by the Services. It also includes providing personalized content and recommendations to you, including by email. Through such features, we are able to bring you information and content tailored to your individual interests and needs. 

**To Contact You.** We may periodically contact you with offers and information about the Services and our affiliates, including in connection with your accounts, online surveys, legal notices, news stories, new features that you are entitled to access, and other important information. You may opt out of receiving commercial email messages from us by following the instructions contained in those email messages. 

**To Deliver Targeted Advertising.  **We may use your information to facilitate the delivery of targeted ads, promotions, and offers to you, on behalf of ourselves and advertisers, on and off the Services. Please see the  **Online Tracking and Advertising** section for further information about our and third parties’ use of cookies, web beacons, mobile ad identifiers, and other tracking technologies to provide you relevant ads, as well as information about how to disable cookies and make other choices related to targeted advertising. 

**To Better Understand Our Readers and Users.  **The Services conduct research on our users’ demographics, interests and behavior based on the information we collect. We do this to better understand and serve our users, and to improve our products and services. 

**To Protect the Rights of the Services and others.  **We may use your personal information as we believe is necessary or appropriate to protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of the Services, its employees or agents, or other users and to comply with applicable law. 

**Consent.** We may otherwise use your information with your consent or at your direction.

The following provides information about entities with which we may share information. Our practices vary depending on the type of information. 

**Affiliates.** We may share information within our family of affiliated companies. 

**Business Partners.** We may also share your information with business partners to provide you with services that you request. For example, if you sign up for a promotion that runs on our Services but that is sponsored or co-sponsored by another company, your information may be shared with that sponsor. SelfHacked is not responsible for the privacy practices of these entities. 

**Service Providers.** We may share information with vendors providing contractual services to us, such as hosting vendors, advertising service providers, and list managers. We also may share your information, including your payment information, as appropriate to process your payments for the Services or complete a transaction. 

**Other Parties When Required by Law or As Necessary to Protect Our Users and Services.  **We may share your personal information as we believe is necessary or appropriate to protect, enforce, or defend the legal rights, privacy, safety, or property of the Services, our employees or agents or users or to comply with applicable law or legal process, including responding to requests from public and government authorities. 

**Logging In Through Social Media Services.  **If you log into the Services with a social media service or if you connect a social media account with the Services, we may share your information with that social media service. The social media services’ use of the shared information will be governed by the social media services’ privacy policy and your social media account settings. If you do not want your information shared in this way, do not connect your social media service account with your Services. 

**Third Parties that Provide Content, Advertising, or Functionality.  **When you use our Services, third parties may collect or receive certain information about you and/or your use of the Services ( _e.g._ , hashed data, click stream information, browser type, time and date, information about your interactions with advertisements and other content), including through the use of cookies, beacons, mobile ad identifiers, and similar technologies, in order to provide content, advertising, or functionality or to measure and analyze ad performance, on our Services or other websites or platforms. This information may be combined with information collected across different websites, online services, and other linked or associated devices. These third parties may use your information to improve their own services and consistent with their own privacy policies. 

**Other Parties in Connection With a Corporate Transaction.  **We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event that we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets to a third party, such as in the event of a merger, acquisition, or in connection with a bankruptcy reorganization. 

**Otherwise With Your Consent or At Your Direction.  **In addition to the sharing described in this Privacy Policy, we may share information about you with third parties whenever you consent to or direct such sharing. 

We also may share other information with third parties in a manner that does not identify particular users, including, for example, aggregated data about how users are using our Services. 

**For users in the EEA and Switzerland** : Please see our Third-Party Partners section at the end of this policy for a list of partners that provide certain features or functionality on the Services ( _e.g._ , content, analytics, advertising, and social media plug-ins) that may use your data, as well as more information about these partners’ use of your data and your rights.

#### Embedded Content and Links to Third-Party Sites and Services

Our Services may embed content from, or link to, third-party websites and services, including social media platforms, that are outside of our control. We are not responsible for the security or privacy of any information collected by other websites or other services. This Privacy Policy does not govern these third party’s content or services, and we encourage you to review the privacy statements applicable to the third-party websites and services you use.

#### How to Access or Update Your Information & Other Privacy Choices Available To You

 **Manage Your selfhacked.com Account.  **You may access or modify your selfhackedt.com account and update your subscriptions provided by the Services by contacting support@selfhacked.com

**Email Promotions.** You may opt out of receiving commercial email messages from us by following the instructions contained in those email messages. 

**Targeted Advertising.** You may choose whether to receive some forms of targeted advertising from many ad networks, audience segment providers, ad serving vendors, and other service providers by visiting the website. Please see the  **Online Tracking and Advertising** section for further information about how to disable cookies and other choices that may be available to you with respect to certain types of targeted advertising.

We have in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online. However, as effective as these measures are, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that the information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.

#### Other Important Information

 **Children’s Privacy.** We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 18 without parental consent, unless permitted by law. If we learn that a child under the age of 18 has provided us with personal information, we will delete it in accordance with applicable law. 

**Your California Privacy Rights.  **(a) California residents are entitled once a year, free of charge, to request and obtain certain information regarding our disclosure, if any, of certain categories of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. We do not share personal information with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. 

**Do-Not-Track Signals and Similar Mechanisms.  **Some web browsers may transmit “do-not-track” signals to the websites with which the user communicates. Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether they even are aware of them. Because there currently is no industry standard concerning what, if anything, websites should do when they receive such signals, the Services currently do not take action in response to these signals. If and when a final standard is established and accepted, we will reassess how to respond to these signals. In the meantime, please see Online Tracking & Advertising for additional information about privacy choices that may be available to you with respect to targeted advertising. 

**International Transfers.  **The Services are headquartered in the United States. Please be aware that if information you provide to us or that we obtain as a result of your use of the Services may be collected in your country and subsequently transferred to the United States or to another country in accordance with applicable law. By using the Services, you consent to the collection, international transfer, storage, and processing of your information

#### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of changes by posting changes here, or by other appropriate means. Any changes to the Privacy Policy will become effective when the updated policy is posted on the Services. Your use of the Services or your provision of personal information to use the Services following such changes indicates your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy.

#### Online Tracking & Advertising

 ** _How We Use Cookies, Web Beacons, and Similar Technologies and How To Disable These Technologies_**

We and third parties that provide content, advertising, or functionality or measure and analyze ad performance on our Services, may use cookies, web beacons, mobile ad identifiers, and similar technologies to facilitate administration and navigation on the Site, to better understand and improve our Services, to determine and/or improve the advertising shown to you here or elsewhere, and to provide you with a customized online experience. 

**Cookies.** Cookies are small files that are placed on your computer when you visit a website. Cookies may be used to store a unique identification number tied to your computer or device so that you can be recognized as the same user across one or more browsing sessions, and across one or more sites. Cookies serve many useful purposes. For example: 

  * Cookies can remember your sign-in credentials so you do not have to enter those credentials each time you visit a Service
  * Cookies can help us and third parties understand which parts of our Services are the most popular because they help us see which pages and features visitors access and how much time they spend on the pages. By studying this kind of information, we are better able to adapt our Services and provide you with a better experience.
  * Cookies help us and third parties understand which ads you have seen so that you don’t receive the same ad each time you access a Service.

Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but can be configured not to do so or to notify the user when a cookie is being sent. If you wish to disable cookies, refer to your browser help menu to learn how to disable cookies. If you disable browser cookies or flash cookies, it may interfere with the proper functioning of the Services. 

**Beacons.** We, along with third parties, also may use technologies called beacons (or “pixels”) that communicate information from your device to a server. Beacons can be embedded in online content, videos, and emails, and can allow a server to read certain types of information from your device, know when you have viewed particular content or a particular email message, determine the time and date on which you viewed the beacon, and the IP address of your device. We and third parties use beacons for a variety of purposes, including to analyze the use of our Services and (in conjunction with cookies) to provide content and ads that are more relevant to you. 

**Local Storage & Other Tracking Technologies. **We, along with third parties, may use other kinds of technologies, such as Local Shared Objects (also referred to as “Flash cookies”) and HTML5 local storage, in connection with our Services. We also may use unique identifiers associated with your device, such as mobile ad identifiers. These technologies are similar to the cookies discussed above in that they are stored on your device and can be used to store certain information about your activities and preferences. However, these technologies may make use of different parts of your device from standard cookies, and so you might not be able to control them using standard browser tools and settings. For HTML5 local storage, the method for disabling HTML5 will vary depending on your browser. For Flash cookies, information about disabling or deleting information contained in Flash cookies can be found [here](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html). 

As described above, we and third parties may use cookies and other tracking technologies to facilitate serving relevant ads to you. For example, these technologies help us determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before, tailor ads to you if you have visited our site before, and avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. 

Due to differences between using apps and websites on mobile devices, you may need to take additional steps to disable tracking technologies in mobile apps. Many mobile devices allow you to opt-out of targeted advertising for mobile apps using the settings within the mobile app or your mobile device. For more information, please check your mobile settings. You also may uninstall our apps using the standard uninstall process available on your mobile device or app marketplace.

#### Users in the EEA and Switzerland

If you are a user in the EEA or Switzerland. the following information applies with respect to personal data collected through your use of our Services. 

**Purposes of processing and legal basis for processing.** We process personal data consistent with our disclosures in this Privacy Policy. We process personal data on the following legal bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to perform our agreement to provide Services to you; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing the Services where those interests do not override your fundamental rights and freedoms related to data privacy. 

**Transfers.  **Personal data we collect may be transferred to, and stored and processed in, the United States or any other country in which we or our affiliates or processors maintain facilities. We will ensure that transfers of personal data to a third country or an international organization are subject to appropriate safeguards. 

**Individual Rights.  **If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, you have certain rights under Chapter 3 of the EU General Data Protection Regulation. To make a request or otherwise exercise your rights under Chapter 3, you can contact us at support@selfhacked.com. In order to respond to your request, we will need to verify your identity and residency and may require you to provide us with supporting information. 

**For More Information**. Please contact us at support@selfhacked.com

#### Advertising Privacy Statement

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies. 

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies. 

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative's multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained. 

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact us at support@selfhacked.com ** ** and contact AdThrive at [info@adthrive.com](mailto:info@adthrive.com). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences icon. (Available in the EU.)

 **SelfHacked relies on third-party partners to provide many of the features or functionality on our platforms (which may include our websites, apps, and newsletters) using data about your use of our platforms as well as other sites.   Below is a list of these partners with links to more information about their use of your data.  This list may be updated from time to time as we add or remove partners from our platforms. **

**You can also see our Privacy Policy above for more information about how we use third-party partners in connection with our services, including to provide you with content, determine and/or improve the advertising shown to you (on our platforms or elsewhere), perform analytics, and allow you to interact with social media platforms.**

**_Please note that this list only applies to the use of our platforms by residents of the EEA and Switzerland._ **

**If you have any questions about any of our third-party partners, you may contact us at: support@selfhacked.com.**

####  Site Operations and Analytics

 We use the following third-party partners to enable features that are necessary for providing you the services on our site and to allow us to understand how our services are being used, track site performance, and improve our services. To learn more about your rights with respect to these partners, including any opt-out rights, you can review their respective privacy policies:

Partner| Learn more about use of data | Opt-out from data use  
---|---  
  
We use the following third parties to deliver advertising, including personalized advertising based on your preferences or interests across services and devices, and to measure and analyze the effectiveness of ads, on our platforms or elsewhere. 

Partner| Learn more about use of data | Opt-out from data use  
---|---  
  
To learn more please view our Cookie Policy and Advertising Policy
